Preliminary Inventory to the Robert Fitch Papers WAG 261
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Robert Fitch Papers
Bulk, 1990-2005
1905-2010, bulk 1990-2005
WAG 261
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
26.5 linear feet (27 boxes)
Fitch, Robert, 1938-
Historical/Biographical Note
Robert "Bob" Fitch was born in Chicago in December 1938. He received a PhD in sociology from the State University of New York (SUNY), Binghampton. A Marxist and prolific writer on many topics, Fitch was particularly concerned with unionism. As well as writing about them, he worked as union organizer for the American Federation of Musicians, Local 802 in New York City during the mid 1980s. Fitch also taught and lectured at universities throughout New York City. He died aged 72 in March 2011.
Scope and Content Note
The Robert Fitch Papers primarily contain Fitch's research materials on different labor unions, particularly in the New York City area. Boxes 25-26, donated after his death in 2011, include personal materials and memorabilia.
NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Arrangement
This collection is unprocessed.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
AFSCME. District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.).; Fitch, Robert, 1938-; Labor unions |x Corrupt practices |z New York (State) |z New York.; Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York
- Inventory
  - NYPL Bibliography re: Jews & Zionism, Internet News Print-Outs re: Jewish Lobby, Politics, Marxism, Israel, Iraq War, Anti-Semitism, Transcript Excerpts, Legal Complaint -- RICO -- against Carpenters and Joiners, Javits Center News & Files, Declaration of Salvatore Miciotta, Mike Billelo Statement, Clean Sweep & Hard Hart Newsletters, Merrimack Pamphlet, Carpenters Union information, 1991-2005 (Box 1)
  - News Articles: Union Movement and Locals, Robert D. Luskin Correspondence, Memoranda, and Testimony, Internet News Print-Outs re: Union Corruption and Declarations -- (Upstate New York, Connecticut, New Jersey) Wendy Sloan Files, Union Correspondence, Messera Clippings/Newsday, Coia Files, Chicago Organizational Chart and News, Legal Files, Testimony to Subcommittees, Newspaper Clippings and Materials re: DC 37, Trial Testimony, and District 37 Booklet, AFSCME Officer Reports, 1994-2004 (Box 2)
  - Handwritten Notes, Correspondence, News Print Outs, Legal Files re: FEC Disclosure Report, Internet News Print-Outs, DOJ Draft Complaint, Chicago Laborers' Meeting, Coia Task, Book Photocopies, News Articles on South Bronx, Newspaper Excerpts re: Airline Strike, Dollars and Democrats Files, US Department of Labor Files, Local 66 Files, Articles re: Mob & Ground Zero, Carpenters Union, SEIU Domestic Care, DC 37 Newspaper Articles, Union Corruption Files, AFT, Tikkun, Buffen Darger, SEIU Files and Labor Notes, 2003-2005 (Box 3)
  - Legal Memoranda, Affidavits, Correspondence, and Newspaper Clippings related to Organized Crime and Corruption, Disbursements, Newspaper Clippings, and E-mails re: Dollars and Democrats, UFCW, Metro Labor Press, Gotti Jr. Files, Labor History Photocopies and Articles, Andrew Cohen Reports and Taft Reports on Corruption, 1990-2001 (Box 4)
  - E-mails concerning Teamsters and State Pension Fund, Old Newspaper Clippings re: Pension Fund (1920s), ULICO Files and News Articles on Finance, FBI Investigation News, US District Court Summons to Segal Advisors, Embezzlement Court Files and Discovery, Pensions and Legal Research, Fascimiles, Fund Advertisements and Distribution Materials, International Law Review, New York Times Articles, Lexus Research, Capital Consults, McAuliffe and Crystal Pensions, 1983-2003 (Box 5)
  - Unite Files: US Investigation, News Articles, Charts and Schedules, Individual Files, Newspaper Photocopies, Legal Testimony on Education and the Workforce, Newsletters: Daily Labor Report, Unite Manuscript, United Pension and Records, Funds, Benefits, DKNY, Punching the Clock Newsletter, Unite Correspondence, Articles and Reports on Sweat Shops, Unite ERISA, Bibliography and Pamphlets, Leaflets, National Labor Committee Reports, JLC Materials, Legal Memoranda, 1998-2004 (Box 6)
  - Campaign Fundraising for the 1996 Election, Tikkun Journal, Teamster Articles, Independent Review Board Reports, US v. International Brother of Teamsters Files, Teamster and Legal Correspondence, Circuit Court Information, News Articles and Print-Outs, Report on Ron Carey, Carey Corruption News, File Drafts, FBI 302's -- 813/809 Teamsters, Pension Debate News, Convoy Dispatch Newspapers, Lombardo Files, Corruption Investigation, Union Sues Pension Fund, Chicago Teamsters' Files, Boston Teamsters, and Wagner - Hoffa Files, 1982-2001 (Box 7)
  - Newspaper Articles, Newsletters, Correspondence, and Cassettes related to the Teamsters Union, Legal Correspondence and Memoranda, Legal Exhibits, Hoffa News Articles, Detroit Teamsters, IRB: Chart of Individual Charges, Teamster Election Files, Hoffa Investigation from Freep Archives, Chicago Files, Sworn Individual Investigations, Union Corruption News Articles and Updates, Hoffa Deposition, Local Files, 2000-2004 (Box 8)
  - Newsletters re: Miami Real Estate, ULLICO 2004 News reports, Handwritten Notes, Receipts, and News re: Teamster Investigation Material, Pension Funds and Sun Valley Material, ULLICO 2001 Annual Report, Correspondence, Application Extension, News, and Legal Complaints re: Department of Labor and Employment, Federal Pension Files and News, Plumbers Union Files, Union Corruption News -- Hollywood, Notecards and Cassette Tapes, 2000-2004 (Box 9)
  - Building Service Story News Articles and Photocopies, SEIU History and News, John Sweeney News Articles and Press Releases, Newspapers, DC 37 Financial Statements, Labor Corruption, Court Proceedings and Indictments, 32 BJ, Employer Charges, Congressional Correspondence, Union Election Material, Booklets and Reports, 32 BJ Benefits, Photographs and Miscellaneous Leaflets, Italian Garment Correspondence, Investigation and Reports on Sweatshops, Carpenters' Union Files, UNITE Material -- Triangle Fire, Health Clinic News Files, Labor Organization Annual Reports and Disbursements, 1966-2001 (Box 10)
  - DC 37 Files: Indictments, Notes, Testimony, Legal Proceedings, Press Releases, Reports on Election, Notes,Correspondence with City College, Newsletters and articles, Office of Labor Relation Forms, AFSCME Booklets: Real Estate and Newsletters, Health Plan of New York Annual Reports, Policy Paper Files, Manuscript Drafts, Health Management Files, Disbursements and Financial Records, 1984-2001 (Box 11)
  - Newsletters, Facsimile, Correspondence, Articles re: New York AFL-CIO, Robert Fitch Manuscript Excerpts, Articles, and Essays, Ron Carey Text, Labor Notes News and New Unity Partnership, SEIU - 32 BJ News, Photocopies and Bibliographical Material, Workers' Socialist News, Labor Advocate: SEIU, American Educational News, LA Times, 1199 SEIU New York State Political Action Fund, SEIU Corruption News, Excerpt of Packets, Carpenters' Union, Culinary Workers' Union, Home Healthcare Material, Boston SEIU Strike and Organizing, 2004 (Box 12)
  - DC 37 News, 2004 Election Material, Roy Comer Legal Material: Plaintiff Motion to Dismiss, Legal Correspondence, Legal Memoranda: Rosenthal v. Roberts and Gray, Union Corruption Updates, Defendants Memorandum of Law in Support of Motion to Dismiss, Deposition Transcript and Affidavit of Lillian Roberts, NY Times Articles on Unions, Health and Human Service Committee Records, DC 37 News, AFSCME Legal Correspondence and Memoranda, Grand Jury Transcripts, Handwritten Notes and Correspondence, Finance and Funds, AFSCME Bonding, Health Plan Audits, Drug Testing, and Benefits, Leaflets and Election Material, The Unionist Newspaper, 1998-2001 (Box 13)
  - Labor History Research Materials and Photocopies, Theodore Christos Liazos George Meany dissertation, George Meany information and News Articles, National Archives Correspondence, Chicago Unions, David Nicholas Lyon Thesis on P.J. McGuire and the American Labor Movement (1870-1890), Cleveland Banking, Palm West, Florida Almanac, Meyer Lanksy Information, Labor Unions: The Mob & Corruption, Derek Bok files, Harvard Law Review, Historical Labor Information and Persons, IBT Files and Handwritten Notes, Parson Student Lists, Herbert Hill Articles, Newsletter: Hart Hat News, Welfare State Articles, 1905-2001 (Box 14)
  - Plumbers - Local 409, Democratic Union Articles and News, SEIU News Articles and Revisions, United Domestic Workers, Carpenters' Union and California Criminal Law, Union Corruption Reports, RICO Trusteeship after Twenty Years: A Progress Report, Venice, Florida Files and Information, Electronic Research Library Materials, Cost and Finance, Sam Parks, Public Affairs Contract, Information and Reports on France, Local 1930 Special Reports, Tikkun Articles, Testimony Committee on Education and the Workforce, Newsletters: Impact, Doug Henwood Article, E-mail exchanges with the Washington Post, Donald Trump Files and News Articles, Teachers' Union Articles, Internet News Print-Outs, 1992-2005 (Box 15)
  - Union Corruption Files, Reports, and Policy, International Law Journals, Federal Probes, New Labor Forum Information, Labor Racketeering Reports, Press Releases, Academic Calendar and Schedule, Sweatshop, Locals Information, Newspaper Articles, United - DOJ Affidavits, Minimum Wage Information, Immigrant Workers, Labor History Files, Unite Newspaper Clippings, Union Corruption (Box 16)
  - Draft Legal Complaints for Laborers LIUNA 212, Executive Summary Decisions, Rulings on Coia charges, Reports to Court, Locals: Newsletters and Correspondence, Legal Correspondence, Documents & Exhibits, Financial Records, Handwritten Notes, News on the Mob, House Judiciary Committee Files, GEB Reports, NYS Laborers Funds, Complaints and Deposition Files, Union Corruption Reports, Louise Furio files, Library and Archival Research, Voice of the Rank and File, Local Pamphlets and Mailers, MTDC Wiretap Information, MTDC Civil Rico, Individual Files, Appeal Court Files, Labor Czar Articles, United Farm Worker Articles, Reports on Wages and International Migration and US Immigration, 1996-2005 (Box 17)
  - Internet News Articles re: Labor and Healthcare, Newsletters, Newspaper Clippings on local politics, Book Reviews, Manuscript Excerpts, Teamsters and UAW, Schedules and Disbursements, Journals: Public Affairs and the UA Journal, Articles on Union Corruption, Legal Indictments, Carpenters' Union Materials, RICO/Corruption Files, ULLICO Facsimile and Correspondence, Handwritten Notes, E-mails, Terry McAuliffe Files, Construction Firm Balance Sheets, Federal Supplements, US v. John Gallo, Lillian Roberts Files, AFL-CIO Executive Council Meeting Materials, Labor Committee Files, Bibliographic Material and Research, Statements, Receipts and Disbursements, 1995-2005 (Box 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Reserve Material, Bibliography, and Research, Legal Correspondence, The Chief Newspapers, News Articles on Labor Chief and Arthur Coia trial, Financial Records and Balance Sheets, Chicago Labor Elections, Individual Files, E-mails, and Legal Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 19)
  - SEIU Notes, Teamsters and Drivers Education Materials, Daily Labor Reports, Labor Corruption Research and Articles, American Spectator Articles, Newspapers: Convoy Dispatch, Legal Opinions and Orders, Teamsters Newsletters, Internet News Articles, 1995-2004 (Box 20)
  - IBT Articles, History and Research, USDA Press Releases, Mailings and Memoranda, E-mails, Magazine Clippings and Newspaper Articles re: Teamsters, Leaflets and Fliers re: Branch Meetings and Fund Raisers, Local Files, Finances, and Conditions, RICO Legal Filings, Information on Hoffa, Referrals, Correspondence to Locals, Individual Files, Quindel Report, 1992-2001 (Box 21)
  - HERE Corruption Files and News Articles, Ron Carey Report, E-mails re: Teamsters, Carpenters' Union News Files, Articles on UAW Corruption, Research and Bibliographic Files, Legal Correspondence, Local Newsletters, Mike Pagano Files, McAuliffe Files, Economic Policy and Institute Reports, Local Files and Memoranda, Newspaper Clippings, Handwritten Notes, Transcripts, 1996-2004 (Box 22)
  - Manuscript Drafts -- Introduction and History, Carpenters' Union Files and General Information, DC 37 Files, Manuscript Drafts - UNITE, Book Reviews, Facsimiles, Correspondence, and E-mails, Union Democracy Review - Newsletter, R. Fitch Articles from Laborers LIUNA, Stardust Drafts, TDU Files and Reports, Mailings to Marty Gottlieb, Public Affairs Contract (Box 23)
  - VPCW & Grupo Gigante News Files, Event Mailings, UFCW Local Contracts & Correspondence, Packinghouse Strike Research, Grocer Strike Files, Hugh Finnamore Files, LA Labor News, Labor Summit Files, Healthcare Information, Professional Pharmacist Files, UPS Strike, LA Janitors, UFCW Newsletters, Tyson Strike, Newspaper Clippings, Labor Publications and Leaflets, Union Corruption News, 2002-2004 (Box 24)
  - Robert Fitch Articles, Lectures, and Essays, Magazines and Journals: In These Times, VLS, Village Voice, The Nation, New Politics, City Limits, Tikkun, Democracy News, Library Files and Notes, Speeches, Newspaper Articles, Manuscripts, Mexico Meeting Minutes, Against the Current, Facsimile, New York Hard Hat News, Labor History Leaflets and Fliers, Print-Outs and Political Commentary, 1970-2010 (Box 25)
  - Diary and Notebooks, Notecards, Memorabilia: Photographs, Name and Birth Certificate, Files on Parents, Assorted Newspapers and Official Documents, Diplomas, CV, Personal Notes and Family Materials, Correspondence, Public Affairs Files, and News Articles, Mixed (Box 26)
  - Sixteen Research(?) Notebooks and Five Audio Cassettes of Fitch on WBAI radio show (Box 27)